PETER BENVENUTO

SENIOR PRODUCT DESIGNER

EXPERIENCE

Senior Product Designer | Mozilla

MAY 2021 - PRESENT, TORONTO, ON

- Owned design of core VPN product to ~60% growth in 3 years
- Conducting discovery, research and execution of major features for VPN product within our team (from ideation to conception)
- Leading org-wide design system audit, rebuild and maintenance
- Assisting with communication of strategy with key stakeholders

Product Designer | Intrado

MAR 2021 - MAY 2021, TORONTO, ON

- Conducting user research and user testing for core SaaS products
- Leading UX/UI design initiatives while following human-centered design thinking best practices
- Collaborating closely with product owners and developers in an agile environment

Software Engineer | InvestCloud Inc.

SEP 2018 - MAR 2021, BURLINGTON, ON

- Developed and shipped products using HTML, CSS and JavaScript
- Develop efficient ETL scripts in Groovy/Java to extract, compute and map client focused financial data
- Design RESTful web APIs to seamlessly extract client data from existing CRM systems

UX/UI Engineer | PlayLine

JUL 2018 - SEP 2018 (CONTRACT), TORONTO, ON

- Maintaining and shipping new features using React and Redux
- Liaised with design team when making design decisions

MENTORING & TEACHING

UX Mentor & Instructor | BrainStation

NOV 2022 - PRESENT, TORONTO, ON

Front End Development Tutor | CareerFoundry

FEB 2022 - PRESENT, REMOTE

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma, User Experience Design

SEP 2020 - DEC 2020, TORONTO, ON

Humber College | Postgraduate Diploma, Marketing

SEP 2016 - 2017, TORONTO, ON

York University | Bachelors, Political Science

SEP 2011 - 2014, TORONTO, ON

peterbenvenuto90@gmail.com 416-456-3019 linkedin.com/in/peter-benvenuto github.com/PeterBen90 peterbenvenuto.com

PROFILE

I'm a Product Designer based in Toronto, ON. I approach problems with a data-informed and empathetic approach, and I have a unique background in software development. My experience allows me to communicate and work with developers effectively in product teams. I specialize in Interaction Design, Design Systems, and Design Strategy.

DESIGN SKILLS

Information architecture,
Wireframing, UI prototyping,
Interaction design, Motion design,
Responsive design, Design systems,
Visual design, User research and
testing, Figma, Sketch, InVision,
InVision Studio, Zeplin, Zeroheight,
Adobe Creative Suite

DEV SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, React, Redux, Material UI, Bootstrap, Bulma, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Java, Groovy, PostgreSQL, SQL, Git, Responsive design

CERTIFICATIONS

Software Engineering - Thinkful Enterprise Design Thinking - IBM